RAJAT SRIVASTAVA

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SUMMARY

Highly effective software developer offering a wealth of around 4 years of relevant expertise. A valuable team player who also is personable and dedicated. Seeking the chance to bring further success to an established organisation through development, testing, and software debugging.

CONTACT

☑ rajatsri94@gmail.com

rajat19.github.io

9910364830

♀ Delhi

in rajatsriv19

najat19

EDUCATION

Ajay Kumar Garg Engineering College, Ghaziabad

BTech Computer Science 2017

Graduated with 80.68%

Member of Open Source R&D Team

Organized Tech Events in College

SKILLS

BACKEND DEVELOPMENT: Node js (Koa/Express),

Python, Java, Typescript, Javascript, SpringBoot

DATA STORES: Mysql, Mongo DB, Cassandra, Redis,

Aerospike

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES: Git, Jenkins, Apache Storm, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Docker, GraphQL, Debezium, Apache Spark

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Jsniper

Node cli based project that creates new projects based on already provided templates. Hosted on npm and github packages

Keep In Touch

Application that reminds its customers to keep in touch with their dear ones. Reminders can be scheduled as per convenience. Build using node.js

Torrent Crawler

Python based command line interface to fetch torrents and subtitles for a movie. Hosted on pypi

Hackerrank Crawler

Crawl Hackerrank Solutions using command line using python. Hosted on pypi

Timetable Management System

Timetable management for college. Options to mark attendance for faculties

EMPLOYMENT

Paytm

Noida

Senior Software Engineer · Sept. 2018 to Current

- Worked on realtime streaming data for processing and analytics purposes
- Worked on distributed computation system like Apache Storm and Spark Streaming
- Worked on Multi-tiered Aggregation System for fraud detection using Apache Spark
- Worked with distributed messaging system for asynchronous processing of rewards for user
- Worked on Integration of ScratchCard Service with Paytm's chat system using Kafka and Storm
- Worked on Core features for Paytm Cricket League and Diwali Tambola Game
- Developed Paytm's Scratch Card System using Java and Mysql
- Developed Paytm's lucky draw feature using Node.js
- Worked on integration of Payment Bank's pipeline with Paytm reward system
- Developed realtime gratification and multiple gratification for Paytm's reward system using Java
- Worked on localisation of apis for Paytm Reward System

Smartprix Web

Noida

Software Developer · June 2017 to Aug. 2018

- Designed Node JS and Vue JS based admin web applications.
- Developed Smartprix new website using Node JS and Marko JS
- Developed Smartrank, an online IDE for test purposes
- Worked on Smartprix Crawler to extract data from appropriate websites
- Worked on Smartprix tiny url service smpx.to

Sysbiome Technologies

Noida

Intern · June 2016 to July 2016

- Developed Samarpan project for recruitment purpose using Laravel
- Wrote all technical documentation for new software
- Developed native Android mobile applications for Samarpan.

Justwravel

Noida

Intern · Sept. 2015 to Nov. 2015

- Worked on JustWravel.com using CodeIgniter framework
- Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes and patch sets for existing web applications

Nisani India

Noida

Intern · May 2015 to Sept. 2015

- Applied knowledge of JavaScript and Object-Oriented Programming to create successful designs-
- Built Student ERP Portal website interface with HTML and CSS